<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sensor Support on hackAIR-Arduino</title>
    <link>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sensor Support on hackAIR-Arduino</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:14:05 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Support matrix</title>
      <link>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/support-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:16:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/support-matrix/</guid>
      <description>   Sensor Name Manufacturer Type Connection Supported Power Saving Support Page     DFRobot PM2.5 DFRobot Laser Serial Yes No Link   SDS011 Inovafit Laser Serial Yes No Link   PPD42NS (Grove) Shinyei LED Pulse Yes No Link   PMS5003 Plantower Laser Serial Yes No Link    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DFRobot PM2.5</title>
      <link>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/dfrobot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:29:07 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/dfrobot/</guid>
      <description>General Information Photo Source: DFRobot Store Page
 Type: Laser Connection: Serial Fan: Yes Power saving: Yes, currently not supported Library Reference: SENSOR_DFROBOT  The sensor comes with a breakout/level shifter board that can be used with the Arduino.
How to connect First connect the sensor to it&amp;rsquo;s breakout daughterboard and then connect that to the Arduino using the following pin assignment:
   Sensor Pin Description Arduino Pin WiFi Shield pin     GND Power Ground GND GND   VCC Power 5V 5V   RST Reset &amp;ndash; &amp;ndash;   RX Receive data 7 STX   TX Transmit data 8 SRX    The board has two more unmarked pins, you can leave those unconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PMS5003</title>
      <link>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/pms5003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:29:07 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/pms5003/</guid>
      <description>General Information  Type: Laser Connection: Serial @ 3.3V Fan: Yes Power saving: Yes, currently not supported Library Reference: SENSOR_PMS5003 Datasheet: Chinese  This sensor is very similar to the DFRobot PM2.5 sensor.
This sensor communicates at 3.3V and does NOT include a level shifter. If you can&amp;rsquo;t use an external level shifter we don&amp;rsquo;t recommend this sensor.
 How to connect According to the datasheet, the pin closest to the sensor&amp;rsquo;s edge is Pin 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDS011</title>
      <link>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/sds011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:55:54 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/sds011/</guid>
      <description>General Information  Type: Laser Connection: Serial Fan: Yes Power saving: &amp;ndash; Library Reference: SENSOR_SDS011  Other sensors of the same family (SDSxxx) are potentially supported since most of them use the same data packet format.
How to connect This sensors comes with a USB-to-Serial adapter. To connect the sensor to the Arduino we recommend cutting the wire that goes to the serial adapter and connecting the wires to the Arduino as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PPD42NS (Grove)</title>
      <link>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/grove/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 13:08:26 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackair-project.github.io/hackAir-Arduino/sensors/grove/</guid>
      <description> General Information  Type: LED Connection: Digital @ 5V Fan: No Power saving: No Library Reference: SENSOR_GROVE  How to connect    Sensor wire Arduino Pin Shield Pin     Red wire 5V 5V   Black Wire GND GND   Yellow wire D8 D8    Specifications  Operating Voltage: 4.95 - 5.05 V Maximum input current: 90mA Operating Temperature Range: 0 - 45 °C Operating Humidity Range: 0 - 95%  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>